EMMA FLEETWOOD

Phone: 0874510376 Nationality: Irish

Email: emmafleetwood@gmail.com Languages: English (native); Spanish

Address: Blackrock, Co.Dublin (advanced)

BACKGROUND

After graduating from university with a degree in languages I worked in a variety of secretarial, reception and administrative positions. I am highly computer proficient and have a copy-typing speed of 65 wpm. I have excellent organisational skills and experience in diary management, accounting, travel planning and records management. I am also a professional cook and have been working in various chef roles for the last six years.

SKILLS

Document preparation

- Copy-typing (65 wpm)
- Audio-typing (Dictaphone)
- Confidential letters, medical reports and documents
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint)

Records Management

- Maintaining and updating manual and electronic filing systems
- Maintaining and updating client databases

Telephone and Switchboards

- Answering, screening, forwarding and making phone calls
- · Confident and pleasant telephone manner

Communications

Organising and distributing incoming and outgoing communications, including:

- post
- fax
- email (Outlook)
- · couriered packages

Reception and Front Desk

- · Greeting clients arriving to the office
- Dealing with client and patient queries in a friendly and courteous manner
- Managing meeting room schedule
- Maintaining a well-presented appearance

General Administration Duties

- Ordering of stationery and office/clinic supplies
- Photocopying
- Binding documents

Diary Management

- Scheduling internal and external meetings
- Organising conference calls
- Organising flights, hotels, taxis and other travel arrangements for department staff

Computer Programs

Experience with:

- SAP
- GP Clinico
- Blackboard

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2017 (one-month temporary assignment)	Accounts Assistant - Health Research Board, Grattan House, Mount Street, Dublin 2 Provided support to the accounts department associated with purchase ledger. Duties included: • Updating accounts payable reconciliations • Logging and scanning invoices and statements • Setting up accounts payable records, banking records and processing payments
June - November 2015; May - June 2016	Module Administrator - UCD School of Medicine, St Vincent's Hospital, Dublin 4 Provided administrative support in the Education and Research Centre. Duties included: • Auditing the surgical tutorial system to identify problems with scheduling and to increase attendance of both students, consultant tutors and surgical tutors • Preparing rotations, schedules and timetables for 250 students • Receiving new students and inducting them (informing them of timetables, rules and orientating them in the hospital)
May - June 2016	Temporary Agency Office Assignments - Southside Personnel/ Orange Recruitment Murnane & Associates Accountants, Monkstown; HSOC Financial Advisors and Business Consultants, Dun Laoghaire; Jennifer Murphy Opticians, Blackrock Provided reception cover and administrative support in all locations.

December 2007	Temporary Agency Office Assignments - Ann O'Brien Office Specialists DHKN Accountants, Dundrum; Campus Oil, Sandyford Industrial Estate
	Provided reception cover in both locations. Managed front desk and switchboard, distributed incoming correspondence, managed diaries and meeting room schedules.
January - July 2005	Secretary - Ernst & Young Financial Services Department, Dublin 2
	Provided secretarial support to two partners and two departments in Financial Services.
November 2002 - May 2003; December 2003 - June 2004	Secretary - John A. O'Brien & Associates (Patent Agents and Intellectual Property Attorneys), Blackrock
	Provided secretarial support to four patent attorneys and one accountant.
June 1995 - January 2007 (part-time)	Secretary - Carysfort Clinic, Blackrock
	Provided secretarial support for 7+ medical staff in a busy clinic

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2018 - present	Freelance Chef I have worked for private and corporate clients in Dublin. I have also worked as a chef in ski chalets and at yoga retreats in various locations.
May 2017 - present	Cookery Tutor - Dublin Cookery School, Blackrock I am currently involved with the various evening and weekend courses at the cookery school, setting up the ingredients for each class of 24 students and teaching them in the on-site kitchen.
December 2015 - December 2016	Volunteer Coordinator - Misión Mexico Children's Home, Tapachula, Mexico Managed a team of volunteers providing care of 40 children from the ages of 18 months to 21 years. Duties included recruitment, training, supervision, budget management and liaising with directors
Oct 2012 - Oct 2013	Baker - Café Aunt Benny, Berlin Responsible for producing all sweet goods and savoury bar snacks
July 2011 - Aug 2012	Chef - East London Restaurant, Berlin Cooked full-time in a busy Modern British restaurant serving updated versions of classic dishes
Nov 2006 – Dec 2009	Personal Chef - Bon Bia Personal Chef Services, Dublin Owner/operator of a personal chef service. Services included: filling clients' freezers with home-cooked meals prepared to clients' requirements; catering; cookery lessons (group and private)

OTHER SKILLS/EDUCATION

- Ballymaloe Cookery School Jan-April 2006 -Highly Commended
- Ballymaloe Cookery School Wine Examination -96%
- Ballymaloe Food Hygiene & HACCP Course
- STCW95 Yacht Safety Course
- Full clean Irish driving licence
- BA Spanish and Italian from University College Dublin
- Leaving Certificate 1999: 1 B1, 6 B2s, including Business Organisation (all honours); 485 points

REFERENCES

Available on request.